Finding aid for Mary L. Bell papers
Detroit Public Library. Burton Historical Collection.
Mary L. Bell papers
1934-1991
00175
Detroit Public Library. Burton Historical Collection.
1.0 Linear feet (2 boxes, 1 large manuscript, 1 extra large manuscript)
Bell, Mary L.
Immediate Source of Acquisiton
00175
Restrictions on Access
This collection is open for research use.
Scope and Contents note
This collection relates to Dr. Haley and Mary Bell's activities in broadcasting, civic affairs, and dentistry.
Biographical/Historical note
Mary Bell was president of Bell Broadcasting Company of Detroit. She cofounded the company with her late husband, Dr. Haley Bell, in 1956. When their station, WCHB, went on the air, it was the third black-owned station in the country. Mrs. Bell graduated from Walden University and is a native of Nashville, Tennessee. She was active in many organizations, including the National Council of Negro women, the Women's Economic Club of Detroit, the NAACP, and the YMCA. (Blue index card)
General Note
See finding aids for complete listing.
African American women executives; Broadcasting; Dentistry; Detroit (Mich.)--Social life and customs.; Photographs.; Plaques (flat objects); Scrapbooks
- Box One
  General note
  Level A: B26N
  - 1. Award presented to Mary Bell by Detroit Club of the National Association of Negro Business and Professional Women's Clubs, 1985.
  - 2. Booker T. Washington Business Association Plaque presented to Dr. Haley Bell, 1961.
  - 3. Plaque presented to Dr. Haley Bell by Meharry Medical College, 1973.
  - 4. Plaque presented to Mary Bell by NAACP, 1978.
- Box Two (Box 2)
  - 1. Key to the city of Detroit presented to Dr. Haley Bell, 1958.
  - 2. Miscellaneous photographs
  - 3. Photograph: Dr. Haley Bell
  - 4. Scrapbook items
  - 5. Plaque presented to Mary Bell by B.A.R.T., 1991.
- Large Box (LMS)
  - 1. Resolution, city of Hamtramck, Michigan, honoring Dr. Haley Bell, 1965.
  - 2. Life Membership plaque (Mary Bell), National Council of Negro Women, n.d.
  - 3. Golden Heritage Life membership plaque, NAACP, presented to Bell Broadcasting Company, 1981.
  - 4. Motown Records Special Achievement Award presented to Dr. Haley Bell, 1973.
- Large Manuscript Folder (LMS)
  Level B
  - 1. Photograph: National Dental Association, Twenty-First annual session, July 10-13, 1934.
  - 2. Special tribute to Mrs. Haley (Mary) Bell, State of Michigan, 79th Legislature, November 21, 1978.